<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Fetcham and Bookham Repair Cafe</title>
    <link>/</link>
      <atom:link href="/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <description>Fetcham and Bookham Repair Cafe</description>
    <generator>Source Themes Academic (https://sourcethemes.com/academic/)</generator><language>en-gb</language>
    <image>
      <url>/images/icon_hu3014f46539b7a11e588b19106fbca813_19575_512x512_fill_lanczos_center_3.png</url>
      <title>Fetcham and Bookham Repair Cafe</title>
      <link>/</link>
    </image>
    
    <item>
      <title>What is a repair café?</title>
      <link>/what/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/what/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Our repair café is an event usually lasting 2.5 hours on the first Saturday of the month where you can bring broken possessions to be fixed by volunteer repairers. You stay with the repairer while the work is being done so that you can see the work being carried out and maybe help yourself. One of the goals is that everyone will one day be able to repair their own items.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;There is no charge, but donations are welcome to help cover costs.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The repair café helps to promote learning new skills and to save waste by less items being dispose off in landfill.
The first repair café was started by Martine Postma in Amsterdam in 2009 and its great success led to the Repair Café Foundation being established. The Foundation provides advice and help in setting up and maintaining repair cafes and also supports campaigns such as the &amp;ldquo;Right to Repair&amp;rdquo; laws requiring manufacturers to make it easy to repair their products and to provide spare parts for at least 10 years.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There are over 2500 repair cafés worldwide with 278 in the UK and the number is growing fast all the time.
For further information on repair cafes please visit:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.repaircafe.org/en/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;https://www.repaircafe.org/en/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To watch a Repair Café in action please visit:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;https://youtu.be/Ur2DH7wG6BY?si=be0A2-ZXcEFZlgvC&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;https://youtu.be/Ur2DH7wG6BY?si=be0A2-ZXcEFZlgvC&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Pre-Registration</title>
      <link>/pre-register/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/pre-register/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;It is now possible to register in advance by following this link:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;httpscalendlycom-links-go-here&#34;&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;https://calendly.com/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;https://calendly.com/&lt;/a&gt; links go here.&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This does not give you priority but could save you time on the day.  If you are able to provide details of your repair item such as the model and what the problem is, this may also enable us to help with suggestions for obtaining a spare part etc.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
